vooberlin.com 2019-04-14

# Privacy | Voo Store Berlin

**Data protection declaration**

Unless stated otherwise below, the provision of your personal data is neither legally nor contractually obligatory, nor required for conclusion of a contract. You are not obliged to provide your data. Not providing it will have no consequences. This only applies as long as the processing procedures below do not state otherwise.  
“Personal data” is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person.

**Server log files**

You can use our websites without submitting personal data. 

Every time our website is accessed, user data is transferred to us or our web hosts/IT service providers by your internet browser and stored in server log files. This stored data includes for example the name of the site called up, date and time of the request, the IP address, amount of data transferred and the provider making the request. The processing is carried out on the basis of Article 6(1) f) GDPR due to our legitimate interests in ensuring the smooth operation of our website as well as improving our services.  

_**Customer account       Orders      **_

 **Customer account**

When you open a customer account, we will collect your personal data in the scope given there. The data processing is for the purpose of improving your shopping experience and simplifying order processing. The processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR with your consent. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us without affecting the legality of the processing carried out with your consent up to the withdrawal. Your customer account will then be deleted.  

**Collection, processing, and transfer of personal data in orders**

When you submit an order we only collect and use your personal data insofar as this is necessary for the fulfilment and handling of your order as well as processing of your queries. The provision of data is necessary for conclusion of a contract. Failure to provide it will prevent the conclusion of any contract. The processing will occur on the basis of Article 6(1) b) GDPR and is required for the fulfilment of a contract with you. 

Your data is transferred here for example to the shipping companies and dropshipping providers, payment service providers, service providers for handling the order and IT service providers that you have selected. We will comply strictly with legal requirements in every case. The scope of data transmission is restricted to a minimum.  

_**Contact       **_ ** __** ** _Evaluations       _** ** _Newsletter       _**

 **Collection and processing when using the contact form  **

When you use the contact form we will only collect your personal data (name, email address, message text) in the scope provided by you. The data processing is for the purpose of making contact. By submitting your message you agree to the processing of your transmitted data. Processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR with your consent.You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us without affecting the legality of the processing carried out with your consent up to the withdrawal. We will only use your email address to process your request. Finally your data will be deleted, unless you have agreed to further processing and use.  

**Data collection when you post a comment  **

When you comment on an article or a contribution, we collect your personal data (name, email address, comment text) only in the scope provided by you. The processing serves to allow you to comment and to display comments. By submitting the comment you agree to the processing of the transmitted data. The processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR with your consent. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us without affecting the legality of the processing carried out with your consent up to the withdrawal. You personal data will then be deleted.  

On publication of your comment the name and email address you have enteredwill be published.

On submission of your comment your IP address will also be saved in order to prevent misuse of the comment function and to ensure the security of our IT systems. By submitting the comment you agree to the processing of the transmitted data. The processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR with your consent. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us without affecting the legality of the processing carried out with your consent up to the withdrawal. Your IP address will then be deleted.

 **Use of your email address for mailing of newsletters**

We use your email address outside of contractual processing exclusively to send you a newsletter for our own marketing purposes, if you have explicitly agreed to this. The processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR with your consent. You can withdraw your consent at any time without affecting the legality of the processing carried out with your consent up to the withdrawal. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time using the relevant link in the newsletter or by contacting us. Your email address will then be removed from the distributor.  

Your data will be forwarded to a service provider for email marketing in the course of order processing. It will not be forwarded to other third parties.

Your data will be transferred to a third country, which is covered by an adequacy decision by the European Commission.

 **Use of your email address for mailing of direct marketing  **

We use your email address, which we obtained in the course of selling a good or service, for the electronic transmission of marketing for our own goods or services which are similar to those you have already purchased from us, unless you have objected to this use. You must provide your email address in order to conclude a contract. Failure to provide it will prevent the conclusion of any contract. The processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR due to our justified interest in direct marketing. _**You can object to this use of your email address at any time by contacting us. You will find the contact details for exercising your right to object in our imprint.**_ You can also use the link provided in the marketing email. This will not involve any costs other than transmission costs at basic tariffs.  

_**Shipping companies        _ ** _ ** _ **Merchandise management       **_**_**_**_

 **Forwarding of your email address to shipping companies for information on shipping status**

We forward your email address to the shipping company in the course of contractual processing, if you have explicitly agreed to this in the order process. The forwarding is for the purpose of informing you by email on the shipping status of your order. The processing will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR with your consent. You can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us or the transport company without affecting the legality of the processing carried out with your consent up to the withdrawal.  

**Use of an external merchandise management system**

We use a merchandise management system in the course of order processing for the purposes of contractual processing. For this purpose your personal data as collected in the course of the order will be sent to

Pickware GmbH, Goebelstr. 21, 64293 Darmstadt  
easybill GmbH, Düsselstr. 21, 41654 Kaarst, Germany 

_**Payment service providers        _ ****_**_

**Using PayPal**  
All PayPal transaction are covered by the PayPal Data Privacy Statement. You can found this at <https://www.paypal.com/de/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full?locale.x=en>

_**Cookies**_

Our website uses cookies. Cookies are small text files which are saved in a user’s internet browser or by the user’s internet browser on their computer system. When a user calls up a website, a cookie may be saved on the user’s operating system. This cookie contains a characteristic character string which allows the browser to be clearly identified when the website is called up again.  
We use these cookies to make our offering more user-friendly, effective and secure. Cookies also allow our systems to recognise your browser after a page change and to offer you services. Some functions of our website cannot be offered without the use of cookies. These services require the browser to be recognised again after a page change.  
Processing is carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR due to our largely justified interest in ensuring the optimal functionality of the website as well as a user-friendly and effective design of our range of services.  
Cookies will be stored on your computer. You therefore have full control over the use of cookies. By choosing corresponding technical settings in your internet browser, you can be notified before the setting of cookies and you can decide whether to accept this setting in each individual case as well as prevent the storage of cookies and transmission of the data they contain. Cookies which have already been saved may be deleted at any time. We would, however, like to point out that this may prevent you from making full use of all the functions of this website.  
Using the links below, you can find out how to manage cookies (or deactivate them, among other things) in major browsers:  
Chrome Browser: <https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?hl=en>  
Internet Explorer:[ https://support.microsoft.com/de-de/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies](http://https//support.microsoft.com/de-de/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)  
Mozilla Firefox: <https://support.mozilla.org/de/kb/cookies-erlauben-und-ablehnen>  
Safari: <https://support.apple.com/de-de/guide/safari/manage-cookies-and-website-data-sfri11471/mac>

_**Analysis       Advertising      Communication      **_

The data processing described subsequently in this section, especially the setting of cookies, will be carried out on the basis of art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR due to our largely justified interest:

\- in the needs-based and target-oriented design of our website, for example, with tools for analysis and statistics

\- in addressing the website visitors in a targeted manner using interest-based advertisement, e.g. using conversion tracking

\- in direct customer communication, for example, using live-chat tools

_**You have the right to veto this processing of your personal data according to art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR, for reasons relating to your personal situation.**_

**Use of Google Analytics  **

Our website uses the web analysis service Google Analytics by Google LLC (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; “Google”). The processing of data serves to analyse this website and its visitors. Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide other services to the website operator relating to website and internet use. The IP address communicated by your browser as part of Google Analytics is not associated with any other data held by Google. Google Analytics uses cookies, which make it possible to analyse your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie regarding your use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. IP anonymisation is activated on this website. Google uses this to shorten your IP address beforehand within Member States of the European Union or in other signatories to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transferred to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Your data may be transmitted to the USA. Following the US-EU Data Protection Agreement, Google has become “Privacy Shield“ certified and is therefore obliged to observe European data protection laws.  You can prevent collection of the data (including your IP address) generated by the cookies and related to your use of the website by Google as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link [<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>]. You can set an opt-out cookie to prevent collection by Google Analytics across devices. Opt-out cookies prevent the future collection of your data when you visit this website. You need to opt-out on all systems and devices in use for this to work comprehensively. If you click here, the opt-out cookie is set: Disable Google Analytics.  

**Use of LiveZilla**  
Our website uses the analysis tool of LiveZilla GmbH (Byk-Gulden-Straße 18, 78224 Singen).The processing of data serves to analyse this website and its visitors. Data is collected and saved for marketing and optimisation purposes. A usage profile can be generated from this data under a pseudonym. Cookies may be deployed for this purpose. Cookies facilitate recognition of your internet browser. The data collected with LiveZilla technologies will not be used to identify the website user personally in future or combined with personal data on the bearer of the pseudonym without the separately issued consent of the affected party. You can prevent the storage of cookies by choosing corresponding technical settings in your internet browser. We would, however, like to point out that this may prevent you from making full use of all the functions of this website.  

**Use of the remarketing or “similar target groups” function by Google  **  
Our website uses the remarketing or “similar target groups” function by Google LLC (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; “Google”). This function serves to analyse visitor behaviour and visitor interests. Google uses cookies to analyse website use, forming the basis for producing interest-related adverts. Cookies allow for the recording of website visits as well as anonymised data on the use of the website. The personal data of website visitors is not saved. If you then visit another website in the Google display network you will then be shown adverts which are more likely to take previous areas of product and information interest into account. Your data may also be transmitted to the USA. Following the US-EU Data Protection Agreement, Google has become “Privacy Shield“ certified and is therefore obliged to observe European data protection laws. For this purpose you can permanently deactivate the use of cookies by following the link below and downloading and installing the plug-in: [support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996?hl=en](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996?hl=den)  
Alternatively, you can deactivate the use of cookies by third parties by calling up the Network Advertising Initiative deactivation page at <https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> and following the opt-out instructions. You can find more detailed information on Google remarketing as well as the associated data protection declaration at: <https://www.google.com/privacy/ads/>  

**Use of Google Ads conversion tracking**  
Our website uses the online marketing programme “Google Ads”, including conversion tracking. Google conversion tracking is a service operated by Google LLC (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; “Google”). If you click on adverts placed by Google, a cookie is placed on your computer for conversion tracking. These cookies have limited validity, do not contain any personal data and thus cannot be used for personal identification. If you visit certain pages on our website and the cookie has not yet expired, we and Google can recognise that you have clicked on the advert and were forwarded to this page. Every Google Ads customer receives a separate cookie. Therefore, it is not possible to track cookies relating to the websites of AdWords customers. The information collected using the conversion cookie serves the purpose of producing conversion statistics. This allows us to find out the total number of users who have clicked on our adverts and were forwarded to a page equipped with a conversion tracking tag. However, they do not receive any information with which could be used to personally identify users. You can prevent the storage of cookies by choosing corresponding technical settings in your internet browser. We would, however, like to point out that this may prevent you from making full use of all the functions of this website. You will then not be included in the conversion tracking statistics.You can also deactivate personalised advertising in Google’s advertising settings. You can find an introduction to this at <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en> You can also deactivate the use of cookies by third parties by calling up the Network Advertising Initiative deactivation page at <https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> and following the opt-out instructions.You will find more information as well as Google’s data protection declaration at: <https://www.google.de/policies/privacy/>  

**Use of Facebook remarketing**  
Our website uses the remarketing function “Custom Audiences” by Facebook Inc. (1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA; “Facebook”).This function serves to address the visitor to the website with interest-related advertising on the social network Facebook. We have implemented Facebook’s remarketing tag on our website for this purpose. This tag sets up a direct connection to Facebook’s servers when you visit our website. This informs the Facebook server which of our web pages you have visited. Facebook assigns this information to your personal Facebook user account. When you visit the social network Facebook you will then be shown personalised, interest-related Facebook ads. Your data may also be transmitted to the USA. Following the US-EU Data Protection Agreement, Facebook has become “Privacy Shield“ certified and is therefore obliged to observe European data protection laws. You can deactivate the remarketing function “Custom Audiences” [here](). You can find more detailed information on Facebook’s collection and use of data, your associated rights and options for protecting your privacy in Facebook’s privacy policy: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>.  

**Use of LiveZilla’s live chat system**  
Our website uses LiveZilla GmbH’s chat system (Byk-Gulden-Straße 18, 78224 Singen).The system serves to facilitate communication between you and us in our role as provider. It also collects and stored information for marketing and optimisation purposes. A usage profile can be generated from this data under a pseudonym.Cookies may be deployed for this purpose. Cookies facilitate recognition of your internet browser. The data collected with LiveZilla technologies will not be used to identify the website user personally in future or combined with personal data on the bearer of the pseudonym without the separately issued consent of the affected party. You can prevent the storage of cookies by choosing corresponding technical settings in your internet browser. After doing this, it is however possible that you will not be able to use all functions of the website fully.  

**_Plug-ins_**

 **Use of YouTube**

Our website uses the function for the embedding of YouTube videos provided by Google Ireland Limited (Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland; “YouTube”). YouTube is an affiliated company of Google LLC (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA;“Google”).  
This feature shows YouTube videos in an iFrame on the website. The option “advanced privacy mode” is enabled here. This prevents YouTube from storing information on visitors to the website. It is only if you watch a video that information is transmitted to and stored by YouTube.

Your data may also be transmitted to the USA. Following the US-EU Data Protection Agreement, Google has become “Privacy Shield“ certified and is therefore obliged to observe European data protection laws. 

Further information on the data collected and used by YouTube and Google, your rights and privacy can be found in YouTube’s privacy policy (<https://www.youtube.com/t/privacy>).  

**Use of GoogleMaps**  
Our website uses Google LLC’s feature for the embedding of Google Ireland Limited (Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland). Google Ireland Limited is an affiliated company of Google LLC (1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA).

This feature visually represents geographical information and interactive maps. Google also collects, processes and uses data on visitors to the website when they call up pages with embedded Google maps. Your data may also be transmitted to the USA. Following the US-EU Data Protection Agreement, Google has become “Privacy Shield“ certified and is therefore obliged to observe European data protection laws.   
Processing is carried out on the basis of art. 6 par. 1 point (f) GDPR due to our justified interest in needs-based and targeted design of the website.  
Further information on the data collected and used by Google, your rights and privacy can be found in Google’s privacy policy at <https://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html>. You also have the option of changing your settings in the data protection centre, allowing you to administer and protect the data processed by Google.

**_Rights of persons affected and storage duration_**

 **Duration of storage  **

After contractual processing has been completed, the data is initially stored for the duration of the warranty period, then in accordance with the retention periods prescribed by law, especially tax and commercial law, and then deleted after the period has elapsed, unless you have agreed to further processing and use.  

**Rights of the affected person**

If the legal requirements are fulfilled, you have the following rights according to art. 15 to 20 GDPR: Right to information, correction, deletion, restriction of processing, data portability. You also have a right of objection against processing based on art. 6 (1) GDPR, and to processing for the purposes of direct marketing, according to art. 21 (1) GDPR.  

Contact us at any time. Our contact details can be found in our imprint.  

You can contact our data protection officers directly at: Herr Özgür Tatlici, service@vooberlin.com

 **Right to complain to the regulatory authority**

You have the right to complain to the regulatory authority according to art. 77 GDPR if you believe that your data is not being processed legally.  

**Right to object**

If the data processing outlined here is based on our legitimate interests in accordance with Article 6(1)f) GDPR, you have the right for reasons arising from your particular situation to object at any time to the processing of your data with future effect.

If the objection is successful, we will no longer process the personal data, unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that outweigh your interests or rights and freedoms, or the processing is intended for the assertion, exercise or defence of legal claims.

If personal data is being processed for the purposes of direct advertising, you can object to this at any time by notifying us. If the objection is successful, we will no longer process the personal data for the purposes of direct advertising.  

last update: 19.11.2018
